Guide to the Margaret S. Mahler Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Videotapes and Film, 1954-1982; Series XII; 10.75 linear feet (16 boxes)
  - Lectures
    - New York Psychoanalytic Institute
      - Lecture 1, Reel 3, 1977; 1; videotape (v-30h) (Box 187)
      - Lecture 2, Reel 1, 1977; 1; videotape (v-30h) (Box 188)
      - Lecture 2, Reel 2, 1977; 1; videotape (v-30h) (Box 189)
      - Lecture 2, Reel 3, 1977; 1; videotape (v-30h) (Box 190)
      - Lecture 3, Reel 1, 1977; 1; videotape (v-30h) (Box 191)
      - Teaching-Reel 1, 1977; 1 (Box 192)
        - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 192D)
      - Teaching: Separation- Individuation-Reel 2, 1977; 1 (Box 193)
        - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 193D)
      - Lecture 1, Tape A, 1977 (Box 163, Folder 2336)
      - Lecture 1, Tape A-1, 1977 (Box 163, Folder 2337)
      - Lecture 1, Questions, 1977 (Box 163, Folder 2338)
      - Lecture 2 (B) (Box 163, Folder 2338)
      - Lecture 2 (B-1), 1977 (Box 164, Folder 2339)
      - Lecture 2, Questions, 1977 (Box 164, Folder 2340)
      - Lecture 3 (C) (Box 164, Folder 2340)
      - Lecture 3 (C-1), 1977 (Box 164, Folder 2341)
    - Manhattan Psychiatric Center Lecture, 1977 April 26 (Box 165, Folder 2342)
  - Oral History
    - Langford Interview (duplicating/use copy), Circa 1970 (Box 165, Folder 2343)
      - Duplicating master [restricted] (Box 165DF2343)
      - Use copy (Box 165UF2343)
    - Raquel Barman Interview 1, 1979 July 23 (Box 165, Folder 2344)
    - Raquel Barman Interview 2 (duplicating/use copy), 1979 July 23 (Box 166, Folder 2345)
      - Duplicating master [restricted] (Box 166DF2345)
      - Use copy (Box 166UF2345)
    - Eleanor Galenson Interview-First Congress of Psychiatry, 1980 (Box 166, Folder 2346)
    - Raquel Berman Interview (duplicating/use copy), 1979 (Box 166, Folder 2347)
      - Duplicating master [restricted] (Box 166DF2347)
      - Use copy (Box 166UF2347)
    - Eleanor Galenson Interview, 1980 (Box 166, Folder 2347)
  - Study Materials
    - Anna and Sylvia, undated (Box 167)
    - Anna and Sylvia-condensed, undated (Box 167)
    - Benjamin-condensed Edited basic film, undated (Box 167)
    - Heather-Longitudinal footage, undated (Box 167)
    - Sylvia-complete, Reels 1 and 2, undated (Box 167)
    - Margaret S. Mahler-50 Minute condensed version, undated (Box 167)
    - The New School-Two Comparative Groups, undated (Box 167)
    - Sarah Lawrence College-Infants and Toddlers, unedited, undated (Box 167)
    - Separation Reactions 1 Parts 1 and 2, undated (Box 167)
    - Separation Reactions 1 Parts 3 and 4, undated (Box 168)
    - Separation Reactions 2 Cross-sectional, undated (Box 168)
    - Basic Film-Final Version, condensed, undated (Box 168)
    - "A Mother and Her Two Daughters", undated (Box 168)
    - "The Difference is the Key", undated (Box 168)
    - Emergence of the Sense of Self of the Human Infant, undated (Box 168)
    - Dr. Mahler at Work-Master's Children's Center, undated (Box 168)
    - "The Self", undated (Box 168)
  - General
    - "Freud"-Episodes 1 and 5 Arts and Entertainment Channel, undated (Box 168)
  - Film
    - Arden House I, 1954 May (Box 169)
    - Anna Freud (Box 169)
    - Nunberg (Box 169)
    - Mahler (Box 169)
    - Arden House II, 1954 May (Box 169)
    - Home again (Box 169)
    - Early children play (Box 169)
    - Mahler and kids, 1954 May (Box 169)
    - Mahler and Jacobson, 1954 May (Box 169)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box 169)
- Writings of Others, 1944-1984; Series XIII; 5 linear feet (13 boxes)
  This material is arranged alphabetically by last name of author. Original ringbinders containing writings of others, which were maintained by Margaret S. Mahler are located at the end of this series. Indexes to both the general writings and the ringbinders are located in box 182.
  - A-Alm, 1980, undated (Box 170, Folder 2348)
  - Alp-As, 1926, 1961, 1966, 1983, undated (Box 170, Folder 2349)
  - B-Ben, 1956, 1957, 1960-1962, 1970, 1971, 1980, undated (Box 170, Folder 2350)
  - Ber, 1966, 1984, undated (Box 170, Folder 2351)
  - Bij, 1960 (Box 170, Folder 2352)
  - Bla, 1972, undated (Box 170, Folder 2353)
  - Blo-Blu, 1967, 1972, 1978, 1979, 1985, undated (Box 170, Folder 2354)
  - Boe-Bye, 1967, 1971, 1974, 1982, 1983, undated (Box 171, Folder 2355)
  - C, 1967, 1971, 1975, 1985 (Box 171, Folder 2356)
  - D, 1964, 1974, 1981 (Box 171, Folder 2357)
  - E-Edg, 1973, 1981, undated (Box 171, Folder 2358)
  - Ehr-Ell, 1951, 1970, 1975, undated (Box 171, Folder 2359)
  - Emd-Eng, 1980, undated (Box 171, Folder 2360)
  - F-Fra, 1950, 1965, 1969, 1980, 1981, undated (Box 171, Folder 2361)
  - Fre, 1950, 1960, 1964, 1966, undated (Box 172, Folder 2362)
  - Fro-Fur, 1959, undated (Box 172, Folder 2363)
  - G-Gol, 1959, 1960, 1971, undated (Box 172, Folder 2364)
  - Gre, 1949, 1969, 1970, 1973, 1976 (Box 172, Folder 2365)
  - H, 1947, 1950-1953, 1957, 1958, 1960, 1972, undated (Box 172, Folder 2366)
  - I, 1960 (Box 172, Folder 2367)
  - J, 1946, 1957, 1966 (Box 172, Folder 2368)
  - K-Ker, 1967, 1971, 1972, 1978, 1980, undated (Box 172, Folder 2369)
  - Ker-Kes, 1960, 1966, 1968, 1983, undated (Box 172, Folder 2370)
  - Kle-Kor, 1959, 1968, 1973, 1974, undated (Box 172, Folder 2371)
  - Kra, undated (Box 173, Folder 2372)
  - Kri-Kup, 1950, 1955, undated (Box 173, Folder 2373)
  - LaPerriere, 1962 August (Box 173, Folder 2374)
  - Le Coq Heron, 1972 Oct, December (Box 173, Folder 2375)
  - L-Loe, 1956, 1958, 1964, 1966, 1968, 1973 (Box 173, Folder 2376)
  - Loe, undated (Box 173, Folder 2377-2379)
  - Loe-Low, 1950, 1967, 1970, 1975, 1978, undated (Box 174, Folder 2380)
  - McD, 1972, 1973, 1975, 1977, 1979, 1980, 1981, 1983, undated (Box 174, Folder 2381-2383)
  - M-Mve, 1949, 1962, 1964, 1965, 1979, 1981, 1984, undated (Box 174, Folder 2384)
  - N, 1966, 1982, 1985 (Box 174, Folder 2385)
  - Pac-Pao, undated (Box 174, Folder 2386)
  - Par, undated (Box 174, Folder 2387)
  - Par, 1972, 1973, undated (Box 175, Folder 2388-2392)
  - Par-Pie, 1958, 1976, 1985, undated (Box 176, Folder 2393)
  - Pin, 1964, 1969, 1979, undated (Box 176, Folder 2394)
  - Pol-Put, 1954, 1961, 1968, 1976 (Box 176, Folder 2395)
  - R-Rie, 1959, 1981, undated (Box 176, Folder 2396)
  - Roi, 1967, undated (Box 176, Folder 2397)
  - Ros, 1964, 1969, 1985, undated (Box 176, Folder 2398)
  - Ros-Rut, 1966, 1968, 1972, 1979, undated (Box 176, Folder 2399)
  - S-Sch, 1960, 1962, undated (Box 177, Folder 2400)
  - Sch-Sha, 1960, 1971, undated (Box 177, Folder 2401)
  - Sha-Ste, 1945, 1960, 1963, 1965, 1971, undated (Box 177, Folder 2402)
  - Stern, D., 1980, 1982, 1983 (Box 177, Folder 2403)
  - Stern, M.-Sze, 1962, 1967-1969, 1982, undated (Box 177, Folder 2404)
  - T, U, V, 1969, 1971, 1982 (Box 177, Folder 2405)
  - W-Wei, 1967, 1970, 1978, undated (Box 177, Folder 2406)
  - Whi, 1969, 1977, undated (Box 177, Folder 2407)
  - Wil, 1979 or 1980 (Box 178, Folder 2408)
  - Wil-Wol, 1966, 1968, 1971, 1973, 1984, undated (Box 178, Folder 2409)
  - Yar-Zet, 1966, undated (Box 178, Folder 2410)
  - Unidentified, 1983, undated (Box 178, Folder 2411-2412)
  - Ringbinder #20, 1967, 1971, 1973, 1975, 1980 (Box 178, Folder 2413)
  - Ringbinder #21, 1954, 1969, 1971, 1974, 1981, undated (Box 178, Folder 2414)
  - Ringbinder #22, 1972, 1975, 1977, 1979, 1980, 1981, 1983, undated (Box 178, Folder 2415-2416)
  - Ringbinder #23, 1980-1982, undated (Box 179, Folder 2417-2418)
  - Ringbinder #24, 1964, 1976-1983, undated (Box 179, Folder 2419-2421)
  - Ringbinder #25, 1950, 1963, 1974, 1980, undated (Box 179, Folder 2422-2423)
  - Ringbinder #26, 1959, 1960, 1964, 1980, 1981, undated (Box 179, Folder 2424-2425)
  - Ringbinder #27, 1944, 1979, 1980, 1983, undated (Box 179, Folder 2426-2427)
  - Ringbinder #28, 1972, 1975, 1976, 1979, 1982, undated (Box 180, Folder 2428-2429)
  - Ringbinder #29, 1968, 1973, 1977, 1981-1983, undated (Box 180, Folder 2430-2431)
  - Ringbinder #30, 1980, 1981, 1983, 1984, undated (Box 180, Folder 2432-2435)
  - Ringbinder #31, 1979-1982, undated (Box 180, Folder 2436-2437)
  - Ringbinder #32, 1982, undated (Box 180, Folder 2438-2439)
  - Ringbinder #32, 1974, 1976, 1979, 1982, undated (Box 181, Folder 2440-2441)
  - Ringbinder #33, 1975, 1979, undated (Box 181, Folder 2442)
  - Ringbinder #34, 1975, 1977, 1980, 1981, 1983, undated (Box 181, Folder 2443-2447)
  - Ringbinder #34A, 1951, 1954, 1958, 1974, undated (Box 181, Folder 2448)
  - Ringbinder #35, 1979, 1983, undated (Box 181, Folder 2449)
  - Ringbinder #36, 1967, 1968, 1979-1983, undated (Box 181, Folder 2450-2452)
  - Writings of Others Index A-Z, undated (Box 182)
  - Ringbinders Index A-Z, undated (Box 182)
- Appendix A: Audiotapes, 1974-1981
  Appendix A contains audiotapes originally located in the Mahler Papers which have been transferred to the Historical Sound Recordings department in Sterling Memorial Library, Yale University.
  - Audiotapes
    - Foundation Material
      - Brochure Committee Meeting. Sony LN C-120, 1978 Jun 15
      - Board Meeting. Realistic C 60, 1980 Jan 17
      - Executive Committee Meeting. Sony LNX 60 (2), 1981 Jan 20
    - Oral History
      - Milton Senn Interview. Capitol 1 Cassette (4), 1977 Dec
      - Evelyn Ringold Interview. Intermagnetics Cassette, 1977
      - Raquel Berman Interview. Sony Compact Cassette (2), 1979 Jul 25
      - Memoirs
        - Realistic C 120, 1980 Jun 27-29
        - TDK DC 60, 1980 Jun 29-30
        - TDK DC 60, 1981 Jan 9
        - TDK DC 60, 1981 Jan 9, 16, 23
        - Maxell UDXLI 60, 1981 Jan 23, Feb 27, Mar 6
        - Maxell UDXLI 60, 1981 Mar 6
        - Maxell UDXLI 60, 1981 Mar 6
        - Mekka C 60, 1981 Mar 13
        - Maxell LN 60, 1981 Mar 27
        - Maxell LN 60, 1981 Mar 27
        - Maxell LN 60, 1981 Mar 27
      - Payne-Whitney Clinic. Maxell LN 60 (2), 1981 Apr 8
      - Kramer, Levy, Mahler Interview. TDK DC 90, 1981 Dec 17
      - Neubauer, Kramer, Mahler Interview. TDK DC 120, 1982 Feb 13
      - Philadelphia, 1982 May 7
    - Presentations
      - "Pioneer Panel", 1974 Aug 1
      - International Association for Child Psychiatry and Allied Professions. Panasonic C 90
      - "Meet the Author" Panel, 1977 Apr 29
      - American Psychoanalytic Association. TDK SD 90 (2)/Sony C 90 (2)
      - "Infantile Psychosis". AMPEX 120, n.d.
    - Study Material
      - "Introduction to Anna and Susan". Sony LN C120, n.d.
    - Personal
      - Birthday Celebration (80th). Capitol Cassette, 1977 May 10
    - Unidentified
      - Stenocette tapes (2), n.d.
      - Unknown (1), n.d.